上帝啊
Oh, my God.
这不可能
That's impossible.
别傻了
Don't be stupid.
六点了
Six o'clock
谢谢  黛西
Thank you, Daisy.
安娜
Anna.
炉火还旺吗？
Is your fire still in?
是的  帕特莫太太
Yes, Mrs Patmore.
仆人们的早餐摆好了吗？
Have you laid the servant's hall breakfast?
好了  帕特莫太太
Yes, Mrs Patmore.
是的  帕特莫太太
卧室的炉火呢？
What about the bedroom fires?
都生好了  帕特莫太太
All lit, Mrs Patmore.
我说你迟了就是迟了
You're late when I say you're late.
你早晚都得习惯的
You'll have to get used to it sooner or later.
好的  帕特莫太太
Yes, Mrs Patmore.
早膳已备好  卡森先生
Breakfast is ready, Mr Carson.
书房收拾妥当了吗？
Is the library tidy?
收拾好了  休斯太太
Yes, Mrs Hughes.
很好  今天要彻底打扫餐厅
Good. I want the dining room given a proper going over today.
他们用完早餐  你们就开始
You can do it when they've finished their breakfast.
很好
Very well.
赶紧回厨房  免得被人瞧见
get back down to the kitchens before anyone sees you.
好的  帕特莫太太
Yes, Mrs Patmore.
世事无常
Nothing in life is sure.
早安  卡森
Good morning, Carson.
早安  老爷
Good morning, my lord.
他们所言当真 ？
Is it true what they're saying?
我想是的  老爷
I believe so, my lord.
恐怕船上还有我们认识的人
I'm afraid we'll know some people on it.
上帝保佑那些下等舱的可怜人儿
God help the poor devils below decks.
船上有熟人吗？
Do we know anyone on board?
你妈妈认识阿斯特一家  至少认识他本人
Your mother knows the Astors, at least she knows him.
我们上个月还和罗斯小姐共进晚餐
We dined with Lady Rothes last month.
我原以为它永不沉没
I thought it was supposed to be unsinkable.
没有高不可攀的山峰
Every mountain is unclimbable until someone climbs it,
没有永不翻沉的船
every ship is unsinkable until it sinks.
我能进来吗？
May I come in?
他们在乘客名单上
They're on the passenger list.
你得告诉玛丽
You must tell Mary.
两个都没被救上来  他是这么说的
Neither of them were picked up, that's what he said.
他是这么说的
That's what he said.
卡劳利先生是老爷的堂兄
Mr Crawley was his lordship's cousin
我以为玛丽小姐才是继承人
I thought Lady Mary was the heir.
她是个女孩  傻丫头
She's a girl, stupid.
女孩不能做继承人
Girls can't inherit.
但现在卡劳利先生已故
But now Mr Crawley's dead
您好
Hello.
那你就推门而入了？
So you pushed in?
我是安娜  女仆领班
I'm Anna, the head housemaid.
不必担心  我自能应对
Don't worry about that, I can manage.
好了  休斯太太
All right, Mrs Hughes,
我来负责这里  谢谢
I'll take over. Thank you.
早上好  贝茨先生  欢迎
Good morning, Mr Bates. Welcome.
我是唐顿庄园的管家  我叫卡森
I am the butler of Downton. My name is Carson.
这位是托马斯  第一男仆
This is Thomas, first footman.
托马斯  领贝茨先生入住
Thomas, take Mr Bates to his room,
带他去看看工作的地方
show him where he'll be working.
多谢各位
Thank you, everyone.
我不觉得这长久得了
I can't see that lasting long.
难道是说我必须戴重孝吗？
Does this mean I'll have to go into full mourning?
我的堂兄和侄子几乎已确定遇难
My first cousin and his son are almost certainly dead.
我们全家都得服丧
We'll all be in mourning.
不  我是说那件事
No, I mean with the other thing.
这些是舞会用的
These for a ball,
鼻烟壶  他收集的
Snuff boxes, he collects them.
可没有一件属于我们  不是吗？
But none of it's ours, is it?
下次别再犯同样的错
Don't make the same mistake next time.
谁知还会不会有下次？
Who says there'll be a next time?
她显然是不愿意服丧
She was certainly reluctant to go into mourning.
不知这次我又做错了什么
I wonder what I've done wrong this time.
我不太确定他能否胜任这份工作
I'm not entirely sure that he'll prove equal to the task.
但这由老爷您决定
But your lordship will be the judge of that.
他像极了他母亲
He was too like his mother
你知道新继承人吗  ？
Do you know the new heir?
我记得我从没见过他
I have never to my knowledge set eyes on him.
亲爱的  我来此并非为了争执
My dear, I didn't come here to fight.
他从未料想到你没生下子嗣
It never occurred to him that you wouldn't have a son.
但如果帕特里克能够迎娶玛丽
But when Patrick had married Mary
可不幸的是  现在
Unfortunately, now...
现在一个陌生人将有权处置我的财产
Now, a complete unknown has the right to pocket my money
问题是保住你的嫁妆  庄园就会破产
The problem is, saving your dowry would break up the estate.
那会毁掉罗伯特这辈子苦心经营的一切
It would be the ruin of everything Robert's given his life to.
唐顿是一所了不起的庄园  贝茨先生
Downton is a great house, Mr Bates.
我们日常起居有规有矩
We live by certain standards
我明白
I know.
贝茨  我的老朋友
Bates, my dear fellow.
我应该想到你们正在用午餐
I should have realised you'd all be at luncheon.
没关系  老爷
Not at all, my lord.
我只想来跟老战友打个招呼
I just want to say a quick hello to my old comrade in arms.
贝茨  我的兄弟  欢迎来到唐顿
Bates, my dear man, welcome to Downton.
谢谢  长官
Thank you, sir.
很抱歉打扰各位  请原谅
I'm so sorry to have disturbed you all. Please forgive me.
你们从没问过
You never asked.
哀伤总是让人又饿又累
Nothing makes you hungrier or more tired than grief.
那之后你感觉好些吗？
Did it make you feel better?
没什么用  可它能打发时间
Not much, but it passed the time.
没有遗体我们没办法举行葬礼
We could hardly have held a funeral without the bodies.
我只做了一点调查
I've only made a few inquiries,
马修·卡劳利是一名律师
Matthew Crawley is a solicitor
曼彻斯特？
Manchester?
他的专长是公司法
His special field is company law.
母亲健在  和他住在一起
His mother is alive and he lives with her.
我知道了
I know.
这真够古怪的
It does seem odd
的确如此
Indeed.
帮个忙
Do me a favour.
这个应该撒在鸡肉上
This is supposed to be sprinkled on the chicken.
求你了  用不了几分钟
please, it won't take a moment.
我们该谈谈限定继承权的事情
We ought to talk about the business of the entail.
是的
Yes.
我懂了
I see.
那你就该羞愧
Then you should be ashamed.
黛西  是你吗？
Daisy, is that you?
谢谢你  莫里
Thank you, Murray.
你的建议我会考虑
You've given me a good deal to think about.
玛丽  请大家进餐厅
Mary, try to get everyone into the dining room.
伊迪丝  请敏特里老爷坐下
Edith, make sure old Lord Minterne sits down.
你可曾想过另一种生活吗？
Do you ever wish you'd gone another way?
不知道  可能有点
I don't know. Maybe.
太不公平了
It's iniquitous.
贝茨干得怎么样？
How's Bates working out?
没问题
It's not a problem.
托马斯
Thomas.
他们从教堂回来  路上就谈完了
They talked it all through on the way back from the church.
妈妈说下个月我们可以改半丧
Mama says we can go into half-mourning next month.
实在没得选了我才会嫁给他
I was only going to marry him if nothing better turned up.
他连老爷的箱子都差点提不动
He can hardly manage His Lordship's cases.
我想您不愿看到
I don't believe you'd like to think
你真贴心
You're a darling.
谢谢
Thank you.
怀念部队里的日子吗  贝茨？
Do you miss the army, Bates?
你不觉得隐瞒实情是很不诚实的吗？
Doesn't it strike you as dishonest not to mention it?
你知道我不愿对此多谈
You know I don't care to talk about all that.
我完全理解你想帮助他的初衷
I fully see why you want to help him.
我只是想给他个机会
I just want to give him a chance.
妈妈  抱歉  我不知您来此
Mama, I'm sorry, no one told me you were here.
它非常方便
It's very convenient.
消息传得真快
News travels fast.
说真的  妈妈  你我心知肚明
Really, Mama, you know as well as I do
你难道不在乎唐顿吗？
Don't you care about Downton?
您觉得呢？
What do you think?
我这一生的精力都倾注在唐顿庄园上
I've given my life to Downton.
我生于斯  也希望死于斯
I was born here and I hope to die here.
我在乎它吗？  我当然在乎！
Do I care about it? Yes, I do care!
你们不会是在争执吧
I hope I don't hear sounds of a disagreement.
很高兴总算有人想起来抗争一下了
I'm glad somebody's putting up a fight.
晚餐已经准备好了  夫人
Dinner is served, my lady.
还有谁也一直梦见泰坦尼克号吗？
Does anyone else keep dreaming about the Titanic?
我老是梦见它
I can't get it out of my mind.
不是吧  消停会吧
Not again. Give it a rest.
黛西  别再想这件事了
Daisy, it is time to let it go.
您在南非肯定见过更惨的吧  贝茨先生？
I expect you saw worse things in South Africa, Mr. Bates?
谈不上更惨  但也够坏
Not worse, but pretty bad.
你很享受战争吗？
Did you enjoy the war?
我想没人享受战争
I don't think anyone enjoys war,
但也有些不错的回忆
but there are some good memories, too.
我也确信肯定是有的
I'm sure there are.
贝茨先生  您能把那个托盘递给我吗？
Mr. Bates, would you hand me that tray?
抱歉
Sorry.
老爷带着葡萄酒进了书房
The Lordship's taken his port to the library.
安娜  格温  上楼帮忙收拾去
Anna, Gwen, go up and help clear away.
我老是记不住
I keep forgetting.
这个是要放到隔壁还是拿回厨房？
Does this go next door or back to the kitchen?
什么事？
What is it?
我觉得你很美
I think you look beautiful.
谢谢你  茜玻  亲爱的
Thank you, Sybil darling.
咱们该下楼了
We should go down.
他们随时都会从车站回来
They'll be back from the station at any moment.
你们都准备好了吗？
You all ready?
很好  大家出门迎接客人吧
Very well. You should go out to greet them.
我想出去  卡森先生
I want to go, Mr. Carson.
我很乐意去
I'd like to be there.
我来帮你吧
I'll give you a hand.
欢迎光临唐顿庄园
Welcome to Downton.
格兰瑟姆夫人  我有个不情之请
Lady Grantham, I've a confession to make,
我记得这个人
I remember this man.
贝茨  你没事吧？
Bates, are you all right?
很好  老爷  对不起
Perfectly, my Lord. I apologise.
贝茨先生
Mr. Bates.
我不知道
I don't know.
不  别告诉你母亲
No, don't tell your mama.
我只是不想有人来打扰我们
I'm only worried the others will want to join us.
什么事情？
What things?
不过是军队的晚宴而已
It's just a regimental dinner.
我不管卡森怎么想
I don't care what Carson thinks.
她说她不来喝茶了
She says she won't come to tea,
不管怎样  真是难为你了
It must be so difficult for you, all the same.
不要多事
Don't stir.
这是你父亲的房子  不是吗？
It's your father's house, isn't it?
你有权利知道房子里的一切
You've a right to know what goes on in it.
这通向哪儿？
Where does this lead?
有人来了！
Someone's coming!
能效劳吗  小姐？
Can I help you, my lady?
我们只是随便看看
We were just exploring.
您是要找托马斯吗  大人？
Were you looking for Thomas, Your Grace?
不  如玛丽小姐所说 我们只是随便看看
No, as Lady Mary said, we've just been exploring.
那您想看看我的房间吗  小姐？
Would you care to explore my room, my lady?
不用了  贝茨  很抱歉打扰你了
Of course not, Bates. I'm sorry to have bothered you.
我们马上就下去
We were just going down.
为什么要向那个人道歉？
Why did you apologise to that man?
他无权干涉我们
It's not his business what we do.
这是我的习惯
It's a habit of mine.
这么说你心意已决？
So you're quite determined?
别担心  卡森
Don't worry, Carson.
我不能要您的钱  老爷
I couldn't take your money, my lord.
下午您和玛丽在小阁楼做什么呢？
What were you and Mary doing in the attics this afternoon?
我们就是随处参观
We were just looking around.
是的  卡森管家
Yes, Mr Carson.
你在干什么  安娜？
What are you doing, Anna?
我不明白他为什么要走
I don't see why he has to go.
这不是你能决定的
It's not up to you.
以你的为人  总能找到容身之处
There's always a place for a man like you.
一夜之间  失去两位继承人  太可怕了
To lose two heirs in one night, it's terrible.
您要放弃所有家产吗？
You'll give up your entire estate?
玛丽小姐是位迷人的女士
Lady Mary is a charming person.
谁娶了她都很幸运
Whoever marries her will be a lucky man.
但那不会是我
It will not, however, be me.
我明早就告辞
I'm leaving in the morning.
晚安
Good night.
难以置信
I don't believe that.
我想跟你在一起
I want to be with you.
你这是威胁我吗？
Are you threatening me?
我有证据
I've got proof.
晚安  休斯太太
Good night, Mrs Hughes.
晚安  卡森先生
Good night, Mr Carson.
你觉得她跟慕钱而来的人结婚会幸福吗？
Do you think she would've been happy with a fortune hunter?
你幸福吗？
Have you been happy?
我真让你觉得幸福吗？
Really, have I made you happy?
真的
Yes.
我这人可比克罗伯勒公爵好多了
I am so much nicer than the Duke of Crowborough.
这得我说了算
I'll be the judge of that.
别以为我会袖手旁观  罗伯特
don't think I'm going to let it rest, Robert.
他和公爵大人赶的是同一班火车
He and His Grace are catching the same train.
再见  公爵
Goodbye, Duke.
再见  贝茨  祝你好运
Goodbye, Bates, and good luck.
也祝您好运  老爷
Good luck to you, my lord.
等等！
Wait!
他想要改变我们的命运
He wants to change our lives.